(Music)
(موسيقى)
What you just heard
ما سمعتموه للتو
are the interactions of barometric pressure, wind and temperature readings
هي تفاعلات الضغط البارومتري، قراءات الرياح ودرجة الحرارة
that were recorded of Hurricane Noel in 2007.
التي تم تسجيلها من إعصار نويل في 2007.
The musicians played off a three-dimensional graph of weather data like this.
قام الموسيقيون بعزف رسم بياني ثلاثي الأبعاد لبيانات الطقس مثل هذا.
Every single bead, every single colored band,
كل خرزة لوحدها، كل شريط ملون لوحده،
represents a weather element
يمثل عنصرا من الطقس
that can also be read as a musical note.
يمكن أن يقرأ كذلك كنوتة موسيقية.
I find weather extremely fascinating.
أجد الطقس فاتنا للغاية.
Weather is an amalgam of systems
الطقس مزيج من الأنظمة
that is inherently invisible to most of us.
واضحة بطبيعتها لمعظمنا.
So I use sculpture and music
لذلك أستخدم النحت والموسيقى
to make it, not just visible,
لجعلها ليس فقط ظاهرة،
but also tactile and audible.
بل كذلك ملموسة ومسموعة.
All of my work begins very simple.
كل أعمالي تبدأ بسيطة جدا.
I extract information from a specific environment
أستخرج المعلومات من محيط معين
using very low-tech data collecting devices --
باستخدام أجهزة غير متطورة لتجميع البيانات --
generally anything I can find in the hardware store.
و عادة كل ما أستطيع إيجاده في متجر المعدات.
I then compare my information to the things I find on the Internet --
ثم أقارن معلوماتي مع الأشياء التي أجدها في الأنترنيت --
satellite images, weather data
صور الأقمار الاصطناعية، بيانات الطقس
from weather stations as well as offshore buoys.
من محطات الأرصاد الجوية وكذلك من العوامات البحرية.
That's both historical as well as real data.
والتي هي في نفس الوقت بيانات تاريخية وحقيقية.
And then I compile all of these numbers on these clipboards that you see here.
ثم أجمع كل هذه الأرقام في هذه الحافظات التي ترون هنا.
These clipboards are filled with numbers.
هذه الحافظات مملوءة بهذه الأرقام.
And from all of these numbers,
ومن كل هذه الأرقام،
I start with only two or three variables.
أبدأ بمتغيرين أو ثلاثة فقط.
That begins my translation process.
التي أستند عليها لبدء عملية الترجمة.
My translation medium is a very simple basket.
فحوى الترجمة لدي هو سلة بسيطة للغاية.
A basket is made up of horizontal and vertical elements.
السلة مصنوعة من عناصر أفقية وعمودية.
When I assign values to the vertical and horizontal elements,
حيث حين أربط القيم بالعناصر الأفقية والعمودية،
I can use the changes of those data points over time
أستطيع استخدام التغييرات في نقاط البيانات تلك مع مرور الوقت
to create the form.
لإنشاء الشكل.
I use natural reed,
أستخدم قصبا طبيعيا،
because natural reed has a lot of tension in it
لأن القصب الطبيعي لديه الكثير من الجهد
that I cannot fully control.
والذي لا يمكنني التحكم فيه كليا.
That means that it is the numbers that control the form,
هذا يعني أن الأرقام هي التي تتحكم في الشكل،
not me.
وليس أنا.
What I come up with are forms like these.
ما خرجت به هو أشكال مثل هذه.
These forms are completely made up
هذه الأشكال مصنوعة بالكامل
of weather data or science data.
من بيانات الطقس أو بيانات علمية.
Every colored bead, every colored string,
كل خرزة ملونة، كل خيط ملون،
represents a weather element.
يمثل عنصر طقس.
And together, these elements, not only construct the form,
وهذه العناصر مجتمعة، لا تنشئ الشكل فقط،
but they also reveal behavioral relationships
لكنها تكشف عن العلاقات السلوكية
that may not come across
والتي قد لا تتضح
through a two-dimensional graph.
من خلال رسم بياني ثنائي الأبعاد.
When you step closer, you actually see
حين تقترب، ترى بالفعل
that it is indeed all made up of numbers.
أنها مصنوعة بالكامل من أرقام.
The vertical elements
العناصر العمودية
are assigned a specific hour of the day.
عينت لها ساعة معينة من اليوم.
So all the way around, you have a 24-hour timeline.
وبالتالي على طول المدار لدينا خط زمني ل24 ساعة.
But it's also used to assign a temperature range.
لكنه مستخدم كذلك لتعيين نطاق درجة حرارة.
On that grid, I can then weave the high tide readings,
على تلك الشبكة، يمكنني نسج قراءات المد العالي،
water temperature, air temperature and Moon phases.
درجة حرارة الماء ودرجة حرارة الهواء والأطوار القمرية.
I also translate weather data into musical scores.
أقوم كذلك بترجمة بيانات الطقس إلى علامات موسيقية.
And musical notation allows me a more nuanced way
ونوتات موسيقية تسمح لي بطريقة متنوعة
of translating information
من ترجمة المعلومات
without compromising it.
بدون إهمال أي جزء منها .
So all of these scores are made up of weather data.
وبالتالي كل هذه العلامات مصنوعة من بيانات الطقس.
Every single color, dot, every single line,
كل لون لذاته ونقطة وكل سطر بعينه
is a weather element.
هو عنصر طقس.
And together, these variables construct a score.
ومجتمعة تكون هذه البيانات علامة.
I use these scores to collaborate with musicians.
أستخدم هذه العلامات للتعاون مع الموسيقيين.
This is the 1913 Trio
هذه تريو 1913
performing one of my pieces
تؤدي إحدى قطعي
at the Milwaukee Art Museum.
في متحف الفن بميلووكي.
Meanwhile, I use these scores as blueprints
في الوقت نفسه، أستخدم هذه العلامات كمخططات
to translate into sculptural forms like this,
لترجمتها إلى أشكال منحوتة مثل هذه،
that function still in the sense
والتي لاتزال حيوية بصورة ما
of being a three-dimensional weather visualization,
كونها تصورات ثلاثية الأبعاد للطقس،
but now they're embedding
لكنهم الآن يدمجون
the visual matrix of the musical score,
المصفوفة البصرية للعلامة الموسيقية،
so it can actually be read as a musical score.
بحيث يمكن أن تقرأ بالفعل كعلامة موسيقية.
What I love about this work
ما أحبه في هذا العمل
is that it challenges our assumptions
هو أنه يتحدى افتراضاتنا
of what kind of visual vocabulary belongs in the world of art, versus science.
حول نوع القاموس البصري المنتمي إلى عالم الفن في مقابل العلم.
This piece here is read very differently
هذه القطعة هنا تقرأ باختلاف شديد
depending on where you place it.
اعتماد على مكان وضعها.
You place it in an art museum, it becomes a sculpture.
إن وضعتها في متحف فني، تصير منحوتة.
You place it in a science museum,
إن وضعتها في متحف علمي،
it becomes a three-dimensional visualization of data.
تصبح تصورا ثلاثي الأبعاد للبيانات.
You place it in a music hall,
تضعها في قاعة موسيقى،
it all of a sudden becomes a musical score.
فتصير فجأة علامة موسيقية.
And I really like that,
ويعجبني ذلك حقا،
because the viewer is really challenged
لأن المشاهد يتعرض للتحدي بالفعل
as to what visual language
من حيث ما إن كانت اللغة البصرية
is part of science versus art versus music.
تنتمي إلى العلم في مقابل الفن أو في مقابل الموسيقى.
The other reason why I really like this
السبب الآخر الذي جعل ذلك يعجبني حقا
is because it offers an alternative entry point
هو أنه يعطي نقطة دخول بديلة
into the complexity of science.
لتعقيد العلوم.
And not everyone has a Ph.D. in science.
فليس الجميع لديهم دكتوراه فلسفة في العلوم.
So for me, that was my way into it.
وبالتالي بالنسبة لي، كان ذلك طريق دخولي إلى عالم العلوم .
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)